<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sagisag</string>
    <string name="todo">TODO</string>
    <string name="it_is_declared_as_the_national_flower_by_governor_general_frank_murphy_in_1934_in_the_philippines_it_is_unusual_for_someone_to_give_sampaguita_to_another_person_as_a_gift_or_as_a_sign_of_adoration_because_it_has_a_lasting_impression_of_being_solely_offered_to_saints">It is declared as the national flower by Governor-General Frank Murphy in 1934. In the Philippines, it is unusual for someone to give Sampaguita to another person as a gift or as a sign of adoration because it has a lasting impression of being solely offered to saints.</string>
    <string name="meaning">Meaning</string>
    <string name="sampaguita">Sampaguita</string>
    <string name="symbolize_purity_fidelity_and_hope">symbolize purity, fidelity, and hope</string>
    <string name="it_was_declared_as_the_national_flower_by_governor_general_frank_murphy_in_1934_in_the_philippines_it_is_unusual_for_someone_to_give_sampaguita_to_another_person_as_a_gift_or_as_a_sign_of_adoration_because_it_has_a_lasting_impression_of_being_solely_offered_to_saints_plus_did_you_know_that_sampaguita_is_not_native_to_the_philippines_and_is_still_not_considered_a_naturalized_species_it_has_a_pantropical_distribution_and_is_commonly_cultivated_in_the_country_for_ornamental_purposes_the_sweet_smelling_flowers_are_often_made_into_garlands_and_perfumery_there_are_more_than_10_species_of_jasminum_in_the_philippines_and_8_species_are_considered_endemic_and_are_not_found_elsewhere_in_the_world">It was declared as the national flower by Governor-General Frank Murphy in 1934. In the Philippines, it is unusual for someone to give Sampaguita to another person as a gift or as a sign of adoration because it has a lasting impression of being solely offered to saints. Plus, did you know that Sampaguita is not native to the Philippines and is still not considered a naturalized species? It has a pantropical distribution and is commonly cultivated in the country for ornamental purposes. The sweet-smelling flowers are often made into garlands and perfumery. There are more than 10 species of Jasminum in the Philippines and 8 species are considered endemic and are not found elsewhere in the world.</string>
    <string name="purity_fidelity_and_hope">Purity, Fidelity, and Hope</string>
    <string name="symbol_of">Symbol of</string>
    <string name="picture_naten_as_a_group">Picture naten as a group</string>
    <string name="known_as_the_national_tree_of_the_philippines_narra_is_a_majestic_reddish_hardwood_tree_reflecting_the_same_resiliency_and_strength_as_that_of_the_filipino_people_historically_on_june_21_1969_the_municipality_of_narra_was_created_by_virtue_of_republic_act_no_5642_signed_by_president_ferdinand_marcos_having_a_title_as_quot_the_rice_granary_of_palawan_quot_municipality_of_narra_is_the_main_rice_producer_of_the_province_of_palawan_additionally_narra_is_a_graceful_tree_with_drooping_branches_that_toss_in_the_trade_winds_short_lived_flowers_usually_appear_in_april_or_may_and_for_a_day_or_two_the_tree_is_a_shimmering_mass_of_fragrant_yellow_blooms_which_then_fall_off_nearly_all_at_once">Known as the National Tree of the Philippines, Narra is a majestic reddish hardwood tree reflecting the same resiliency and strength as that of the Filipino people. Historically, on June 21, 1969, the Municipality of Narra was created by virtue of Republic Act No. 5642 signed by President Ferdinand Marcos. Having a title as \"The Rice Granary of Palawan\" Municipality of Narra is the main rice producer of the Province of Palawan. Additionally, Narra is a graceful tree with drooping branches that toss in the trade winds. Short-lived flowers usually appear in April or May, and for a day or two the tree is a shimmering mass of fragrant yellow blooms, which then fall off nearly all at once.</string>
    <string name="lofty_ideals_of_filipino">Lofty Ideals of Filipino</string>
    <string name="history_and_background">History and Background</string>
    <string name="narra">Narra</string>
</resources>